{
    "id": "cdb557c8714247ebb4a3613a9a04c718",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Has the situation ………………………?",
            "description": "We use the past participle form of the verb after has, have and had.",
            "answers": [
                "improved",
                "been improved",
                "improving"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7429110e4d2f4899bc5826259180da99"
        },
        {
            "question": "The accused ………………………… the verdict with anxiety.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to simply state that something happened in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "waited",
                "awaited",
                "had awaited"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c84d6e5dffcb43e9a066115a386b09ee"
        },
        {
            "question": "A wide spread outbreak of plague …………………………… in the 14th century.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to simply state that something happened in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "has occurred",
                "occurred",
                "was occurred"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "385ec74a773147e7857f296bb1baff08"
        },
        {
            "question": "He did not ………………………… any of the samples presented to him.",
            "description": "We use the infinitive (the first form of the verb) after do, does and did. ",
            "answers": [
                "take",
                "took",
                "taken"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d166c92c22314d6dbb08a44f48eb5c7c"
        },
        {
            "question": "Last month I ………………………. to Canada to see my brother.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to simply state that we did something at a past time. ",
            "answers": [
                "went",
                "have gone",
                "had gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "72bf267cf4704d44be9cf4af3f349b0a"
        },
        {
            "question": "There is no use phoning now. They must …………………………..",
            "description": "We can use the structure must have + past participle to predict the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "have gone",
                "had gone"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1d047d5690a74f06976be4349e103379"
        },
        {
            "question": "None of them ……………………… up.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "turned",
                "was turning",
                "turning"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2ee209c89b7a46f5ba077122c16fa1e3"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………………. much of his spare time in the library.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about habits and preferences. ",
            "answers": [
                "spend",
                "spends",
                "is spending"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ba4da5f41ced4e82bfd8c970aa8e3b76"
        },
        {
            "question": "We were …………………………… to hear the news.",
            "description": "Saddened is the past participle form of sadden.",
            "answers": [
                "saded",
                "sadden",
                "saddened"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "aea9f26f2cb843ddaaf3ba1d77531d27"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………….. ill for a week when his brother came.",
            "description": "We use the past perfect to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and had continued until another event took place.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "576fe095f38c4ede9bd0b7eae34f2d25"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………………… hurry, we have got plenty of time.",
            "description": "When need is used as a modal auxiliary, questions and negatives are made without do.",
            "answers": [
                "need not to",
                "need not",
                "don't need"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "14740b4439e54509bdcf934c2bd4fd74"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………… visit my parents every Sunday now I go once a month.",
            "description": "We use used to to talk about past habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "used to",
                "use to",
                "will"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "510fb4fb313544dcadd3331bbdd8a6f1"
        }
    ]
}